# TAMEGYE KOUCHOU BORIS

Via Quintino sella 5 | Vercelli, 13100, Italy | +393248196750 | <u>20053883@studenti.uniupo.it</u>

Date of birth: 15/05/1997 Gender: Male Nationality: Cameroonian

# **OBJECTIVE**

I intend to use this position as a steppingstone to align my experiences and know-how in Life Sciences and Public Health to the advancement of health research. The expertise I hope to improve while working on this project will equip me with the necessary skills to build a career in Public Health.

#### EDUCATION

# Master's degree in medical biotechnologies

University of Eastern Piedmont | Novara, Italy.

Oct 2022 – July 2024

Major in Public Health

CGPA - 107/110

Relevant courses: Biomedical Statistics, Big Data Analysis, Epidemiology, Functional Genomics, Virology.

## Bachelor's degree in biomedical sciences

University of Dschang | Dschang, Cameroon.

Oct 2016 - Jul 2019

Major in epidemiology

CGPA - 2.8/4

Relevant courses: Epidemiology of Infectious Diseases, Biostatistics, Medical Microbiology.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Data analyst - National civil service

Council of Vercelli | Department of Civil Protection

May 2024 - present

- I use QGIS to delineate catchment areas of dams, river courses and streams through the project "Environmentally".
- I clean and analyze environmental safety data with R, create visual dashboards in Power BI, support in building databases and updating the departmental website.

## Academic intern

Global health center (CRIMEDIM) | UPO

April 2023 - July 2024

- I studied epidemic outbreaks in armed conflicts and how infectious diseases spread in conflicting environments.
- Performed reviews and participated in health surveys of migrants in Italy.

## Community health worker

Great Step Initiative | Ogoja, Nigeria.

• Community outreach with vaccination and infant nutrition programs.

May 2020 - July 2022

• Health promotion in the areas of hygiene and sexual reproduction in adolescents and adults in the Adagom refugee settlement.

# Field epidemiologist

Department of Public Health | University of Dschang

June 2017 - Feb 2018

- I designed questionnaires to investigate the association between water quality, hygiene and the occurrence of infectious diseases.
- Through home visits, I manually collected data in the Dschang health district.
- I entered and analyzed collected data in Epi-Info and presented relevant findings to health authorities with recommendations.

#### WORKSHOPS

Clinical trials - Design, implementation and evaluation | January 2023.

**Modelling in life sciences** - Introduction to mathematical and statistical models and their applications in biomedicine | March 2023.

## AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Presidential Excellence award 2018 | UNICORE 4.0 study grant 2022 | EDISU – Scholarship 2023

# TECHNICAL SKILLS ————————————

Proficient in R | Working knowledge in STATA, QGIS and Power BI

### LANGUAGES

English – Mother tongue | French – Fluent | Italian – Working knowledge

### SOFT SKILLS

Diligent | Collaborative | Independent | Goal oriented | Teachable | Organized | Resilient | Perspicacious

#### REFERENCES

Professor Gianluca Gaidano | <u>gianluca.gaidano@med.uniupo.it</u> Alice Masini, PhD | <u>alice.masini@uniupo.it</u>